Consider the Possibilities
Bob & Carol & Ted & Alice is a comedy, drama film directed by Paul Mazursky.
After returning to Los Angeles from a group therapy session, documentary filmmaker Bob Sanders and his wife, Carol, find themselves
becoming vigilante couples counselors, offering unsolicited advice to their best friends, Ted and Alice Henderson.
Not wanting to be rude, the Hendersons play along, but some latent sexual tension among the four soon
comes bubbling to the surface, and long-buried desires don't stay buried for long.
Carol Sanders, played by Natalie Wood.
Bob Sanders, played by Robert Culp.
Ted Henderson, played by Elliott Gould.
Alice Henderson, played by Dyan Cannon.
Horst, played by Horst Ebersberg.
Emilio, played by Lee Bergere.
Bob & Carol & Ted & Alice is a 1969 American comedy-drama film directed by Paul Mazursky, written by Mazursky and Larry
Tucker, who also produced the film, and starring Natalie Wood, Robert Culp, Elliott Gould, and Dyan Cannon.
The original music score was composed by Quincy Jones.
The cinematography for the film was by Charles Lang.
The film received four Academy Award nominations,
including ones for Gould and Cannon.
Patricia Welles wrote the paperback novelization
from Mazursky and Tucker's screenplay.
The film explores themes of friends, therapy, polyamory, foursome.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.